{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Which of the following statements is accurate for the PCR â€“ polymerase chain reaction? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Automated PCR machines are called thermal cyclers",
        "b": "A thermostable DNA polymerase is required",
        "c": "Millions of desired DNA copies can be produced from microgram quantities of DNA",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Which of the following is an application of using Polymerase Chain Reaction?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "DNA cloning",
        "b": "Medical diagnostics",
        "c": "Forensic analysis ",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Primers used for PCR are ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Single-stranded DNA oligonucleotide",
        "b": "Double-stranded RNA oligonucleotide",
        "c": "Double-stranded DNA oligonucleotide ",
        "d": "Single-stranded RNA oligonucleotide"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Taq polymerase used for DNA amplification in PCR is isolated from",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Thermus Aquaticus",
        "b": "Homo Sapiens",
        "c": "Saccharomyces Cerevisiae ",
        "d": "Escherichia Coli"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. Which of the following is not a component of the PCR reaction mixture?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "dNTPs",
        "b": "DNA ploymerase",
        "c": "RNA polymerase ",
        "d": "Primers"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. DNA polymerase used in PCR must have the following characteristics",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Thermostability",
        "b": "High fidelity",
        "c": "High processivity ",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. How many types of dNTPs are required for PCR?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1",
        "b": "2",
        "c": "3 ",
        "d": "4"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Optimum GC content for primer design for PCR must be in the range of",
      "answers": {
        "a": "40%- 60%",
        "b": "90%- 100%",
        "c": "20%- 30% ",
        "d": "80%- 90%"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) was invented by ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Kary Mullis",
        "b": "Ulrich K. Laemmli",
        "c": "Arne Tiselius ",
        "d": "Maurice Wilkins"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. Which of the following is  a thermostable polymerase? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Pfu polymerase",
        "b": "Taq polymerase",
        "c": "Both a and b ",
        "d": "DNA polymerase III"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
